They should have left him alone.
The Bourne Supremacy is a action, drama, thriller
film directed by Paul Greengrass.
A CIA operation to purchase classified Russian documents is blown by a rival agent, who then
shows up in the sleepy seaside village where Bourne and Marie have been living.
The pair run for their lives and Bourne, who promised retaliation should anyone from his former life
attempt contact, is forced to once again take up his life as a trained assassin to survive.
Jason Bourne, played by Matt Damon.
Marie Helene Kreutz, played by Franka Potente.
Ward Abbott, played by Brian Cox.
Nicky Parsons, played by Julia Stiles.
Kirill, played by Karl Urban.
Danny Zorn, played by Gabriel Mann.
The Bourne Supremacy is a 2004 American action-thriller film
featuring Robert Ludlum's Jason Bourne character.
Although it takes the name of the second Bourne novel
(1986), its plot is entirely different.
The film was directed by Paul Greengrass from a screenplay by Tony Gilroy.
The second installment in the Bourne film series after The Bourne Identity (2002), it stars Matt
Damon as Jason Bourne, a former CIA assassin suffering from psychogenic amnesia.
In the film, Bourne is attempting to learn more of his past as he is once more
enveloped in a conspiracy involving the CIA and Operation Treadstone.
Actors Franka Potente, Brian Cox, Gabriel Mann, and Julia Stiles reprise their roles as
Marie Kreutz, Ward Abbott, Danny Zorn and Nicky Parsons, respectively.
Karl Urban and Joan Allen join the cast as Kirill
and Pamela Landy, respectively.
The Bourne Supremacy premiered at the ArcLight Hollywood on July 15, 2004, and was theatrically released in the United States on July 23, by
Universal Pictures It received positive reviews and was a commercial success, grossing $290 million on a $75 million budget.
The film was followed by The Bourne Ultimatum (2007), The
Bourne Legacy (2012), and Jason Bourne (2016).
The film explores themes of sniper, assassin, berlin,
germany, amnesia, based on novel or book.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.